

## Erim Bora Konuk

St.-Nikolaus-Platz 3 | 80939 Munich erimborakonuk@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/erimborakonuk/

+393280473126

Born: 31. March 1995 in Antalya (Turkey)

#### SHORT PROFILE

MSc. Mechanical Engineering graduate specializing in renewable energy, with solid project management and mechanical design experience. Proficient in MATLAB, SolidWorks, and Ansys Fluent, as well as English and Turkish, while actively working to improve German and Italian skills. Demonstrated success in the energy sector through various research, engineering, and leadership roles.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Apr 2023

## **MSc. In Mechanical Engineering**

Polytechnic University of Turin, Italy

- Thesis: A Technology-Informed Accessibility Metric for Site Selection of Offshore Renewable Energy Systems: A Case Study in Europe
- Publication: On the Definition of a Comprehensive Technology-informed Accessibility Metric for Offshore Renewable Energy Site Selection
- Projects: Wind Turbine Blade Recycling, Wind Farm Feasibility Study, Wave
  Energy Converters Farm Design, Hydraulic PTO Technology Research in Wind
  Energy, Thermal Energy Storage Simulation, Borehole Heat Exchanger Analysis,
  Geothermal Heat Pump Design, Meshing Strategies for CFD Simulations in Vehicle
  Design

#### July 2018

## **BSc.** in Mechanical Engineering

Ege University, Izmir, Turkey

- Thesis: Numerical Determination of The Performance of a Non-Traditional Wind Turbine with Wings In The Archimedes Spiral Form
- Publication: Numerical Determination of The Performance of a Non-Traditional Wind Turbine with Wings In The Archimedes Spiral Form

# WORK EXPERIENCE

### Sept – Nov 2022

#### Research Intern - Energy Engineering

MOREnergy Lab, Turin, Italy

- Developed MATLAB algorithm to calculate offshore energy farm's accessibility
- Analyzed offshore locations accessibility across Europe

#### May 2019 – Aug 2020

#### **Mechanical Engineer**

Tupras, Izmir Refinery, Turkey

- Led 20 technicians team overseeing reliability and mechanical integrity of over 1,000 equipment pieces, including turbines, compressors, cooling fans, and pumps
- Identified and analyzed potential issues in rotating equipment, reducing operational costs by \$2 million annually
- Revamped sealing systems technology, enhancing operational conditions of 200 pumps by 20%

#### Aug 2018 – May 2019

## **Project Engineer**

CMS Wheels, Izmir, Turkey

- Managed new production plant construction in cross-functional teams
- Formulated detailed project plan tracking mechanical, electrical, and construction progress with MS Project
- Implemented new layout in mechanical facilities, enhancing pipeline efficiency by approximately 15%

#### Jan – Aug 2018

## **Working Student in Production Engineering**

CMS Wheels, Izmir, Turkey

- Implemented new tool changeover car and analyzed setup times, reducing downtime by 16%
- Initiated root cause analysis and corrective actions, eliminating defects by 6% per month

## EXTRA - CURRICULAR

#### Feb 2021 – Jan 2022

#### **Lead Mechanical Designer**

ExMAH – PoliTo student team designing (SolidWorks), analyzing (Inspire and Nastran), and building (Low force SLA 3D printer) a prosthetic hand.

- Expertly used SolidWorks for 3D mechanical design
- Contributed to the development and assembly of the prosthesis using advanced lowforce SLA 3D printing technology

#### Oct 2015 – Jun 2016

#### Co-Founder

Ege Entrepreneurship Society

- Established a dynamic student organization at Ege University, dedicated to promoting entrepreneurship and fostering personal growth among members.
- Organized and participated in various high-profile events, including the "entresting." conference, which hosted prominent figures from the entrepreneurship ecosystem and attracted over 800 attendees

## **SKILLS**

Engineering	****	SolidWorks	***	AutoCAD
Software	★★★☆☆	Ansys Fluent	★★★☆☆	Siemens Star-CMM+
	★★☆☆☆	Simulink	***	WAsP
Programming	****	MATLAB	***	Python
	★★★☆☆	Visual Basic	***	Java
General IT	****	MS Office	***	MS Project
Skills	***	SAP PM & MM	***	Linux
Languages	****	English	★☆☆☆☆	German
	***	Italian	****	Turkish